<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-17T02:26:28-05:00</updated><id>/</id><subtitle>The #YesWeCode Fund is a partnership of organizations committed to increasing access to technology education for all. The scholarship fund is designed to remove financial barriers for people who are underrepresented in the technology industry, including women and people of color. Students with financial need are encouraged to apply to receive a full-tuition scholarship to attend a full-time, immersive code school and take the first step toward a fulfilling career in technology.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">$100 Million #YesWeCode Fund to Improve Diversity in Tech; Applications Now Open for Code School Scholarships</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/15/press-release-announcing-fund.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="$100 Million #YesWeCode Fund to Improve Diversity in Tech; Applications Now Open for Code School Scholarships" /><published>2017-03-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/15/press-release-announcing-fund</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/15/press-release-announcing-fund.html">&lt;p&gt; The partners from the Tech Opportunity Fund and #YesWeCode, announced that applications for the newly renamed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&quot; onclick=&quot;linkClick(this.href)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;#YesWeCode Fund&lt;/a&gt; are now open. The announcement was made on Saturday at a luncheon panel hosted by Van Jones, Founder of Dream Corps and #YesWeCode, at the 2017 HBCU@SXSW. Additional panelists included Tess Posner, Managing Director of TechHire; Sam Kapila, Director of Academic Operations &amp;amp; Diversity at The Iron Yard; Derrick Morgan, Co-Founder of Huddle Ventures; Rodney Sampson, partner at TechSquare Labs; and John Hope Bryant, Founder, Chairman and CEO of Operation HOPE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The #YesWeCode Fund, initially launched as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/09/prweb13673546.htm&quot; onclick=&quot;linkClick(this.href)&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tech Opportunity Fund&lt;/a&gt; in September 2016, is a collaboration between The Iron Yard, Code Fellows, Operation HOPE, Opportunity Ecosystem, Climb Credit, TechSquare Labs, We Can Code IT and #YesWeCode. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education. In addition to technical skills training, the initiative will include core financial literacy education and entrepreneurship training through Operation HOPE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The tech divide requires a collaborative effort to close the gap between the underrepresented who want a more promising future and the companies requiring a much-needed change in the makeup of the industry,” said Felix Flores, Jr., National Director of #YesWeCode. “The #YesWeCode Fund models how the fight for social justice and tech innovation can be a synergistic win for all. We’re honored to partner with The Iron Yard and TechSquare Labs to take our work to nearly 20 cities in the near future to help maintain the tech industry as the pioneers of innovative and positive change.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#YesWeCode is a Dream Corps initiative that works with partners to help connect 100,000 underrepresented minorities to careers in technology. The program accelerates access to training in high-demand technical and non-technical skills to prepare untapped talent to enter the tech-fueled economy. #YesWeCode works to build a diverse pipeline of &amp;#39;homegrown&amp;#39; tech talent to meet demand and boost local economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“SXSW represents the global innovation economy and to go live with a diversity and inclusion initiative of this magnitude during our HBCU@SXSW experience is epic,” said Rodney Sampson, a partner of the Fund and partner at Opportunity Ecosystem and TechSquare Labs. “What started as a conversation during a TechHire event in Atlanta between Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard, Megan Smith, former Chief Technology Office of the U.S., and myself, is now a reality. Together, we will train and support thousands of new software engineers who otherwise might not have been able to pursue a career in tech.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next five years, the #YesWeCode Fund aims to award $100 million in diversity scholarships to women and minority students who are currently underrepresented in the tech workforce. The Iron Yard has committed $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to the school’s immersive programs, Code Fellows has committed $5 million in scholarships, We Can Code IT will offer $1 million in full-tuition scholarships, and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach the goal of awarding $100 million in scholarships, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com/partners/&quot;&gt;the Fund is calling for&lt;/a&gt; employers, code schools and civic organizations across the country to join the effort by providing funding for scholarships and contributing resources that will support scholarship recipients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Creating an inclusive tech workforce can only be achieved if all stakeholders in the tech sector are represented in the solution,&amp;quot; said Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard. &amp;quot;By uniting the efforts of employers, educators, government and civic organizations in the Fund, we can both inspire people who are currently underrepresented in the industry to choose tech as a career and empower them to pursue that goal through a full-tuition scholarship to attend a code school.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Access to opportunity is the hallmark of an inclusive economy,” Bryant said. “This extraordinary collaborative will help develop life skills in deserving students, many, in underserved communities throughout the nation—creating a generation of tech leaders and job creators to power us forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applications for #YesWeCode Fund scholarships are now open. To receive a scholarship, applicants will need to first be accepted into a participating code school through that program’s standard admissions process. Students will then receive a link to apply for the scholarship from the participating program. Scholarships will be awarded to qualified students on a first come, first served basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the scholarship program, or to learn how your organization or code school can be involved in the #YesWeCode Fund, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;#YesWeCode Fund&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The #YesWeCode Fund is a scholarship initiative designed to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to quality tech education. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government bodies, civic organizations and employers across the country, the Fund aims to award $100 million in code school diversity scholarships over the next five years and help graduates of the program begin rewarding, lifelong careers in the technology industry. For more information, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The partners from the Tech Opportunity Fund and #YesWeCode, announced that applications for the newly renamed #YesWeCode Fund are now open. The announcement was made on Saturday at a luncheon panel hosted by Van Jones, Founder of Dream Corps and #YesWeCode, at the 2017 HBCU@SXSW. Additional panelists included Tess Posner, Managing Director of TechHire; Sam Kapila, Director of Academic Operations &amp;amp; Diversity at The Iron Yard; Derrick Morgan, Co-Founder of Huddle Ventures; Rodney Sampson, partner at TechSquare Labs; and John Hope Bryant, Founder, Chairman and CEO of Operation HOPE. The #YesWeCode Fund, initially launched as the Tech Opportunity Fund in September 2016, is a collaboration between The Iron Yard, Code Fellows, Operation HOPE, Opportunity Ecosystem, Climb Credit, TechSquare Labs, We Can Code IT and #YesWeCode. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education. In addition to technical skills training, the initiative will include core financial literacy education and entrepreneurship training through Operation HOPE. “The tech divide requires a collaborative effort to close the gap between the underrepresented who want a more promising future and the companies requiring a much-needed change in the makeup of the industry,” said Felix Flores, Jr., National Director of #YesWeCode. “The #YesWeCode Fund models how the fight for social justice and tech innovation can be a synergistic win for all. We’re honored to partner with The Iron Yard and TechSquare Labs to take our work to nearly 20 cities in the near future to help maintain the tech industry as the pioneers of innovative and positive change.” #YesWeCode is a Dream Corps initiative that works with partners to help connect 100,000 underrepresented minorities to careers in technology. The program accelerates access to training in high-demand technical and non-technical skills to prepare untapped talent to enter the tech-fueled economy. #YesWeCode works to build a diverse pipeline of &amp;#39;homegrown&amp;#39; tech talent to meet demand and boost local economies. “SXSW represents the global innovation economy and to go live with a diversity and inclusion initiative of this magnitude during our HBCU@SXSW experience is epic,” said Rodney Sampson, a partner of the Fund and partner at Opportunity Ecosystem and TechSquare Labs. “What started as a conversation during a TechHire event in Atlanta between Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard, Megan Smith, former Chief Technology Office of the U.S., and myself, is now a reality. Together, we will train and support thousands of new software engineers who otherwise might not have been able to pursue a career in tech.” Over the next five years, the #YesWeCode Fund aims to award $100 million in diversity scholarships to women and minority students who are currently underrepresented in the tech workforce. The Iron Yard has committed $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to the school’s immersive programs, Code Fellows has committed $5 million in scholarships, We Can Code IT will offer $1 million in full-tuition scholarships, and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach the goal of awarding $100 million in scholarships, the Fund is calling for employers, code schools and civic organizations across the country to join the effort by providing funding for scholarships and contributing resources that will support scholarship recipients. &amp;quot;Creating an inclusive tech workforce can only be achieved if all stakeholders in the tech sector are represented in the solution,&amp;quot; said Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard. &amp;quot;By uniting the efforts of employers, educators, government and civic organizations in the Fund, we can both inspire people who are currently underrepresented in the industry to choose tech as a career and empower them to pursue that goal through a full-tuition scholarship to attend a code school.&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Access to opportunity is the hallmark of an inclusive economy,” Bryant said. “This extraordinary collaborative will help develop life skills in deserving students, many, in underserved communities throughout the nation—creating a generation of tech leaders and job creators to power us forward.” Applications for #YesWeCode Fund scholarships are now open. To receive a scholarship, applicants will need to first be accepted into a participating code school through that program’s standard admissions process. Students will then receive a link to apply for the scholarship from the participating program. Scholarships will be awarded to qualified students on a first come, first served basis. For more information about the scholarship program, or to learn how your organization or code school can be involved in the #YesWeCode Fund, visit: http://www.yeswecodefund.com. #YesWeCode Fund The #YesWeCode Fund is a scholarship initiative designed to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to quality tech education. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government bodies, civic organizations and employers across the country, the Fund aims to award $100 million in code school diversity scholarships over the next five years and help graduates of the program begin rewarding, lifelong careers in the technology industry. For more information, visit: http://www.yeswecodefund.com.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Can Code IT Partners with $100 Million Scholarship Fund for Women &amp;amp; Minorities Pursuing Tech Careers</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/14/we-can-code-it-announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Can Code IT Partners with $100 Million Scholarship Fund for Women &amp; Minorities Pursuing Tech Careers" /><published>2017-03-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/14/we-can-code-it-announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/14/we-can-code-it-announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund.html">&lt;p&gt;Reposted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://wecancodeit.org/2017/03/14/we-can-code-it-partners-with-yes-we-code-fund/&quot;&gt;We Can Code IT Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CLEVELAND, Ohio &amp;#8212; March 13, 2017 &amp;#8212;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; We Can Code IT is the premier coding boot camp in Cleveland and Columbus with a mission to increase diversity in the tech industry. They are proud to announce their partnership in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yeswecode.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;#YesWeCode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; Fund for women and minorities. The new scholarship was announced on Saturday in Austin, Texas at the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opportunityhub.co/2017hbcusxsw/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;2017 HBCU@SXSW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; (South by Southwest), an incubator of cutting-edge technologies and digital creativity in partnership with several Historically Black Colleges and Universities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;more-6126&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The #YesWeCode fund aims to award $100 million in full-tuition scholarships over the next five years for women and minorities to attend code school and pursue careers in technology. Initially &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/09/prweb13673546.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;launched as the Tech Opportunity Fund in September 2016&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the fund is a collaboration between &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theironyard.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wecancodeit.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We Can Code IT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codefellows.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Code Fellows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://operationhope.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Operation HOPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opportunityhub.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Opportunity Ecosystem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.climbcredit.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Climb Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techsquare.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;TechSquare Labs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;,  and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yeswecode.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;#YesWeCode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, a Dream Corps initiative helping connect 100,000 underrepresented minorities to careers in technology. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Unifying the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the #YesWeCode Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education. In addition to technical skills training, the initiative will include core financial literacy education and entrepreneurship training through programming partner Operation HOPE. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We Can Code IT is a perfect partner for the #YesWeCode fund because we’ve created coding bootcamp academies where women and minorities feel understood and welcomed,” says Leslie Evans, President of We Can Code IT. Her organization is offering a full tuition scholarship in each of their classes or “cohorts” in Cleveland and Columbus for the next five years.  After being accepted as a student at We Can Code IT, interested students can apply at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“We’re honored to partner with The Iron Yard and other well-respected organizations,” says Mel McGee, founder and CEO of We Can Code IT. “The #YesWeCode fund is a really exciting way to close the gap and literally change the face of the tech industry. We want to create promising futures for people you don’t normally see in software development and computer programming.” McGee says the #YesWeCode Fund also meets the booming demand of organizations and businesses hungry for more diversity and the innovation it brings to IT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard has committed $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to the school’s immersive programs, Code Fellows has committed $5 million and We Can Code IT will offer $1 million in full-tuition scholarships.  Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To reach the goal of awarding $100 million in scholarships, the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com/partners/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Fund is calling for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; employers, code schools and civic organizations across the country to join the effort by providing funding for scholarships and contributing resources that will support scholarship recipients.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;Creating an inclusive tech workforce can only be achieved if all stakeholders in the tech sector are represented in the solution,&amp;#8221; said Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard. &amp;#8220;By uniting the efforts of employers, educators, government and civic organizations in the Fund, we can both inspire people who are currently underrepresented in the industry to choose tech as a career and empower them to pursue that goal through a full-tuition scholarship to attend a code school.&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;Access to opportunity is the hallmark of an inclusive economy,” said John Hope Bryant, Operation HOPE Founder, Chairman, and Chief Executive Officer. “This extraordinary collaborative will help develop life skills in deserving students, many, in underserved communities throughout the nation—creating a generation of tech leaders and job creators to power us forward&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Applications for #YesWeCode Fund scholarships are now open. To receive a scholarship, applicants will need to first be accepted into a participating code school, including We Can Code IT, through that program’s standard admissions process. Students will then receive a link to apply for the scholarship from the participating program. Scholarships will be awarded to qualified students on a first come, first served basis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To apply for the scholarship program or to learn how your organization or code school can be involved in the #YesWeCode Fund, visit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;_______________________________________________________________________&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;#YesWeCode Fund&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The #YesWeCode Fund is a scholarship initiative designed to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to quality tech education. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government bodies, civic organizations and employers across the country, the Fund aims to award $100 million in code school diversity scholarships over the next five years and help graduates of the program begin rewarding, lifelong careers in the technology industry. For more information, visit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;We Can Code IT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We Can Code IT teaches people how to code, with a special emphasis on inclusion and diversity in tech. With locations in Cleveland and Columbus, We Can Code IT is bridging the gap for those underrepresented in tech by graduating 80% women and people of color. Founded by a female developer with over 20 years of experience, WCCI is a diverse group of experienced programmers and teachers who provide the training and career support that students need. Interested students can take a free online assessment and register for full time or part time courses at &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wecancodeit.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;WeCanCodeIT.org.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Reposted from We Can Code IT Blog</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Iron Yard Announces the #YesWeCode Fund</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/11/announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Iron Yard Announces the #YesWeCode Fund" /><published>2017-03-11T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-03-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/11/announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2017/03/11/announcing-the-yes-we-code-fund.html">&lt;p&gt;Reposted from &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/2017/03/13/yeswecode-fund-application-now-open/#more-6562&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-7037 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586-300x225.jpg 300w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586-768x576.jpg 768w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586-1024x768.jpg 1024w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/IMG_9586-960x720.jpg 960w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend at SXSW, we had the honor of sitting alongside leaders from DreamCorps, #YesWeCode, TechHire and TechSquare Labs to announce that applications for the newly renamed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&quot;&gt;#YesWeCode Fund&lt;/a&gt; are now live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The #YesWeCode Fund was initially &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;launched as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/2016/09/09/announcing-tech-opportunity-fund/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tech Opportunity Fund&lt;/a&gt; in September 2016 and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; is a collaboration between &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theironyard.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codefellows.org&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Code Fellows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://operationhope.org&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Operation HOPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opportunityhub.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Opportunity Ecosystem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.climbcredit.com&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Climb Credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techsquare.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;TechSquare Labs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wecancodeit.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;We Can Code IT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yeswecode.org&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;#YesWeCode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a huge goal and we are proud to be a part of the solution. Our CEO, Peter Barth said it best: &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;Creating an inclusive tech workforce can only be achieved if all stakeholders in the tech sector are represented in the solution. By uniting the efforts of employers, educators, government and civic organizations in the Fund, we can both inspire people who are currently underrepresented in the industry to choose tech as a career and empower them to pursue that goal through a full-tuition scholarship to attend a code school.&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-7053 alignleft&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2-225x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;206&quot; height=&quot;275&quot; srcset=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2-225x300.jpg 225w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2-960x1280.jpg 960w, http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/Image-uploaded-from-iOS-2.jpg 1224w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next five years, the #YesWeCode Fund aims to award $100 million in diversity scholarships to women and
minority students who are currently underrepresented in the tech workforce. We have committed $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to attend our immersive programs, and Code Fellows and We Can Code IT &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;have also committed to providing scholarships to attend their bootcamp courses&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are so excited to be working with such fantastic organizations around the country, and cannot wait to meet the new students who will have the opportunity to learn to code and pursue a career in tech through the Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For more information about the scholarship program, or to learn how your organization or code school can be involved in the #YesWeCode Fund, visit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&quot;&gt;http://www.yeswecodefund.com&lt;/a&gt; or shoot us an email at info@yeswecodefund.com. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Reposted from The Iron Yard Blog</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Tech Opportunity Fund’ Launched to Award $100 Million in Code School Diversity Scholarships</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/tech-opportunity-fund-launched-award-100-million-code-school-diversity-scholarships.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="‘Tech Opportunity Fund’ Launched to Award $100 Million in Code School Diversity Scholarships" /><published>2016-09-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/tech-opportunity-fund-launched-award-100-million-code-school-diversity-scholarships</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/tech-opportunity-fund-launched-award-100-million-code-school-diversity-scholarships.html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Partnership created by The Iron Yard, Code Fellows and Operation HOPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Over the next five years, the Tech Opportunity Fund aims to award $100 million in full-tuition diversity scholarships to participating code school programs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Operation HOPE, and other nonprofits and government agencies, will provide financial literacy education and support services to propel students through their transition into tech careers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Announcement mentioned today in speech by Vice President Joe Biden in St. Louis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;WASHINGTON &amp;#8211; (September 9, 2016) &amp;#8211;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theironyard.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;, the largest immersive code school in the U.S., today launched the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopportunityfund.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tech Opportunity Fund&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; in collaboration with with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codefellows.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Code Fellows&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.operationhope.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Operation HOPE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;By unifying&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the Tech Opportunity Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education for all. In addition to technical skills training, the initiative will include core financial literacy education and entrepreneurship training through programming partner Operation HOPE. The Tech Opportunity Fund was mentioned this morning in a speech by Vice President Joe Biden in St. Louis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“To maximize the potential of the tech industry, we must maximize the potential of a diverse tech workforce,” said Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard. “The Tech Opportunity Fund builds off of the momentum generated by innovative initiatives like TechHire to ensure Americans of all backgrounds have access to tech training programs that can open the door to a career in tech. There is a true need in the industry for an organization to unite the many groups that are working toward this goal and by coordinating our efforts, we can truly change the industry for the better.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Over the next five years, the Tech Opportunity Fund aims to award $100 million in diversity scholarships to in-need students from groups that are currently underrepresented in the tech workforce including women and minorities&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard has committed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt; $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to the school’s immersive programs over the next five years, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Code Fellows has committed $5 million in full-tuition scholarships, and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach the goal of awarding $100 million in scholarships, the Tech Opportunity Fund is calling on employers, code schools and civic organizations across the country to join the Fund by providing funding for scholarships and contributing resources that will support for scholarship recipients. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;&amp;#8220;The creation of the Tech Opportunity Fund is unprecedented,” said Rodney Sampson, a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;partner of the Tech Opportunity Fund and partner at TechSquare Labs. “By far, it is the largest tangible strategic financial commitment to diversify the technical talent and workforce that will drive our nation toward an inclusive innovation economy for all. I look forward to working with all of the stakeholders to ensure that these scholarships are distributed with integrity and authenticity.&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;In addition to providing full-tuition scholarships to code school programs, the Tech Opportunity Fund will work to remove other barriers that can prevent people from pursuing a code school education. Partnerships with city-level government bodies and civic organizations will assist scholarship recipients by addressing needs such as affordable housing, financial literacy, counseling and transportation as needed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“There is no one-size-fits-all solution that will increase access to tech education and improve diversity in the workforce,” said Barth. “The Tech Opportunity Fund approaches these issues holistically and coordinates local and national resources to provide students with both academic opportunity and the support system they need to be successful.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Access to opportunity is the hallmark of an inclusive global economy, and access to digital opportunity and jobs in the digital space is the door to the future,” said John Hope Bryant, Operation HOPE Founder, Chairman and CEO. “This extraordinary collaborative will help develop life skills in deserving students, many, in underserved communities throughout the nation—creating a generation of tech leaders and job creators to power us forward.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Applications for Tech Opportunity Fund scholarships will open by January 2017. To receive a scholarship, applicants will need to first be accepted into a participating code school through that program’s standard admissions process. After their acceptance, students will apply for a Tech Opportunity Fund scholarship through the website, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopportunityfund.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.techopportunityfund.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;. Scholarships will be awarded to qualified students on a first come, first served basis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“Over the last 12 months, we’ve provided over $600,000 in scholarships, from direct funds and from great partners like Expedia and Zillow Group. These funds have given over a hundred students the chance to learn relevant, highly desirable skills, and continue on to join great companies in the local tech markets,” said Dave Parker, Code Fellows CEO. “The Tech Opportunity Fund program helps us expand that impact.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Scholarships will be available on all of The Iron Yard and Code Fellows’ campuses:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Atlanta, GA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Durham, NC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Orlando, FL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Austin, TX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Greenville, SC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Charleston, SC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Houston, TX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Raleigh, NC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Charlotte, NC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Indianapolis, IN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Salt Lake City, UT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Cincinnati, OH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Las Vegas, NV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;San Antonio, TX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Columbia, SC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Minneapolis, MN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Seattle, WA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Dallas, TX&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Nashville, TN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Tampa, FL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Detroit, MI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;New York, NY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Washington, DC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For more information and to learn more about how your organization or code school can be involved, visit: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopportunityfund.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.techopportunityfund.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;About The Iron Yard&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The Iron Yard is one of the world’s largest and fastest-growing code schools. It exists to create real, lasting change for people, companies and communities through technology education. The school offers full-time programs in Back-End Engineering, Front-End Engineering, Mobile Engineering and Design. The Iron Yard operates more than 20 campuses in the U.S. For more information, visit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theironyard.com&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.theironyard.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Code Fellows&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Code Fellows is an immersive coding bootcamp in Seattle, WA, training aspiring software developers of all levels in industry-relevant technologies and helping them transition into high-value tech careers. They have over 270 hiring partners and 650 graduates in the industry, with an average starting salary of $71k and a 95% successful placement rate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;To learn more about Code Fellows, visit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.codefellows.org&amp;amp;esheet=50799027&amp;amp;newsitemid=20140206005943&amp;amp;lan=en-US&amp;amp;anchor=www.codefellows.org&amp;amp;index=3&amp;amp;md5=fc342d877386693431dee24feff201ea&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.codefellows.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Operation HOPE&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Since 1992, Operation HOPE has been moving America from civil rights to &amp;#8220;silver rights&amp;#8221; with the mission of making free enterprise and capitalism work for the underserved. Through its core programs, the nonprofit has provided financial dignity and economic empowerment to over 2.6 million individuals worldwide, and $2 billion in economic activity for the disenfranchised—turning check cashing customers into banking customers, renters into homeowners, small business dreamers into small business owners and minimum wage workers into living wage consumers.  Project 5117 is HOPE’s multi-year four-pronged approach to combating economic inequality that aims to improve financial literacy, increase business role models and business internships for youth, and stabilize the American dream by boosting credit scores. Operation HOPE recently received its second consecutive 4-star charity rating for fiscal management and commitment to transparency and accountability by the prestigious non-profit evaluator, Charity Navigator—further establishing it as a best-in-class organization. For more information:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.operationhope.org/&quot;&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;www.OperationHOPE.org &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;###&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Partnership created by The Iron Yard, Code Fellows and Operation HOPE Over the next five years, the Tech Opportunity Fund aims to award $100 million in full-tuition diversity scholarships to participating code school programs Operation HOPE, and other nonprofits and government agencies, will provide financial literacy education and support services to propel students through their transition into tech careers Announcement mentioned today in speech by Vice President Joe Biden in St. Louis WASHINGTON &amp;#8211; (September 9, 2016) &amp;#8211; The Iron Yard, the largest immersive code school in the U.S., today launched the Tech Opportunity Fund in collaboration with with Code Fellows and Operation HOPE. By unifying the efforts of code schools, government, civic organizations and employers, the goal of the Tech Opportunity Fund is to increase diversity in the tech industry by removing financial barriers and increasing access to tech education for all. In addition to technical skills training, the initiative will include core financial literacy education and entrepreneurship training through programming partner Operation HOPE. The Tech Opportunity Fund was mentioned this morning in a speech by Vice President Joe Biden in St. Louis. “To maximize the potential of the tech industry, we must maximize the potential of a diverse tech workforce,” said Peter Barth, CEO of The Iron Yard. “The Tech Opportunity Fund builds off of the momentum generated by innovative initiatives like TechHire to ensure Americans of all backgrounds have access to tech training programs that can open the door to a career in tech. There is a true need in the industry for an organization to unite the many groups that are working toward this goal and by coordinating our efforts, we can truly change the industry for the better.” Over the next five years, the Tech Opportunity Fund aims to award $100 million in diversity scholarships to in-need students from groups that are currently underrepresented in the tech workforce including women and minorities. The Iron Yard has committed $40 million in full-tuition scholarships to the school’s immersive programs over the next five years, Code Fellows has committed $5 million in full-tuition scholarships, and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach the goal of awarding $100 million in scholarships, the Tech Opportunity Fund is calling on employers, code schools and civic organizations across the country to join the Fund by providing funding for scholarships and contributing resources that will support for scholarship recipients. &amp;#8220;The creation of the Tech Opportunity Fund is unprecedented,” said Rodney Sampson, a partner of the Tech Opportunity Fund and partner at TechSquare Labs. “By far, it is the largest tangible strategic financial commitment to diversify the technical talent and workforce that will drive our nation toward an inclusive innovation economy for all. I look forward to working with all of the stakeholders to ensure that these scholarships are distributed with integrity and authenticity.&amp;#8221; In addition to providing full-tuition scholarships to code school programs, the Tech Opportunity Fund will work to remove other barriers that can prevent people from pursuing a code school education. Partnerships with city-level government bodies and civic organizations will assist scholarship recipients by addressing needs such as affordable housing, financial literacy, counseling and transportation as needed. “There is no one-size-fits-all solution that will increase access to tech education and improve diversity in the workforce,” said Barth. “The Tech Opportunity Fund approaches these issues holistically and coordinates local and national resources to provide students with both academic opportunity and the support system they need to be successful.” “Access to opportunity is the hallmark of an inclusive global economy, and access to digital opportunity and jobs in the digital space is the door to the future,” said John Hope Bryant, Operation HOPE Founder, Chairman and CEO. “This extraordinary collaborative will help develop life skills in deserving students, many, in underserved communities throughout the nation—creating a generation of tech leaders and job creators to power us forward.” Applications for Tech Opportunity Fund scholarships will open by January 2017. To receive a scholarship, applicants will need to first be accepted into a participating code school through that program’s standard admissions process. After their acceptance, students will apply for a Tech Opportunity Fund scholarship through the website, www.techopportunityfund.org. Scholarships will be awarded to qualified students on a first come, first served basis. “Over the last 12 months, we’ve provided over $600,000 in scholarships, from direct funds and from great partners like Expedia and Zillow Group. These funds have given over a hundred students the chance to learn relevant, highly desirable skills, and continue on to join great companies in the local tech markets,” said Dave Parker, Code Fellows CEO. “The Tech Opportunity Fund program helps us expand that impact.” Scholarships will be available on all of The Iron Yard and Code Fellows’ campuses: Atlanta, GA Durham, NC Orlando, FL Austin, TX Greenville, SC Portland, OR Charleston, SC Houston, TX Raleigh, NC Charlotte, NC Indianapolis, IN Salt Lake City, UT Cincinnati, OH Las Vegas, NV San Antonio, TX Columbia, SC Minneapolis, MN Seattle, WA Dallas, TX Nashville, TN Tampa, FL Detroit, MI New York, NY Washington, DC For more information and to learn more about how your organization or code school can be involved, visit: www.techopportunityfund.org. About The Iron Yard The Iron Yard is one of the world’s largest and fastest-growing code schools. It exists to create real, lasting change for people, companies and communities through technology education. The school offers full-time programs in Back-End Engineering, Front-End Engineering, Mobile Engineering and Design. The Iron Yard operates more than 20 campuses in the U.S. For more information, visit www.theironyard.com About Code Fellows Code Fellows is an immersive coding bootcamp in Seattle, WA, training aspiring software developers of all levels in industry-relevant technologies and helping them transition into high-value tech careers. They have over 270 hiring partners and 650 graduates in the industry, with an average starting salary of $71k and a 95% successful placement rate. To learn more about Code Fellows, visit www.codefellows.org. About Operation HOPE Since 1992, Operation HOPE has been moving America from civil rights to &amp;#8220;silver rights&amp;#8221; with the mission of making free enterprise and capitalism work for the underserved. Through its core programs, the nonprofit has provided financial dignity and economic empowerment to over 2.6 million individuals worldwide, and $2 billion in economic activity for the disenfranchised—turning check cashing customers into banking customers, renters into homeowners, small business dreamers into small business owners and minimum wage workers into living wage consumers. Project 5117 is HOPE’s multi-year four-pronged approach to combating economic inequality that aims to improve financial literacy, increase business role models and business internships for youth, and stabilize the American dream by boosting credit scores. Operation HOPE recently received its second consecutive 4-star charity rating for fiscal management and commitment to transparency and accountability by the prestigious non-profit evaluator, Charity Navigator—further establishing it as a best-in-class organization. For more information: www.OperationHOPE.org ###</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Announcing the Tech Opportunity Fund</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/announcing-the-tech-opportunity-fund.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing the Tech Opportunity Fund" /><published>2016-09-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/announcing-the-tech-opportunity-fund</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/09/announcing-the-tech-opportunity-fund.html">&lt;p&gt;Today, we are excited to announce the launch of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopportunityfund.org/&quot;&gt;Tech Opportunity Fund&lt;/a&gt;, a partnership of organizations committed to providing $100 million in diversity scholarships to deserving students who want to enter the tech industry. We&amp;#8217;ve joined with Code Fellows and OperationHOPE to lead this effort, and this morning, Vice President Joe Biden included the Fund in a speech he gave in St. Louis!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At The Iron Yard, we&amp;#8217;ve committed to $40 million in full-tuition scholarships over the next five years. Code Fellows has committed to $5 million in scholarships and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach our goal of $100 million in scholarships, we&amp;#8217;ll need even more employers, code schools and civic organizations to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.theironyard.com/2016/09/09/tech-opportunity-fund-launched-award-100-million-code-school-diversity-scholarships/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the full press release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2016/09/09/listen-vice-president-biden-training-americans-jobs-future&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the White House blog post including the Tech Opportunity Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to join us? Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techopportunityfund.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.techopportunityfund.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today, we are excited to announce the launch of the Tech Opportunity Fund, a partnership of organizations committed to providing $100 million in diversity scholarships to deserving students who want to enter the tech industry. We&amp;#8217;ve joined with Code Fellows and OperationHOPE to lead this effort, and this morning, Vice President Joe Biden included the Fund in a speech he gave in St. Louis! At The Iron Yard, we&amp;#8217;ve committed to $40 million in full-tuition scholarships over the next five years. Code Fellows has committed to $5 million in scholarships and Operation HOPE will serve as the Fund’s financial literacy and entrepreneur training partner. To reach our goal of $100 million in scholarships, we&amp;#8217;ll need even more employers, code schools and civic organizations to join us. Click here for the full press release. Click here to read the White House blog post including the Tech Opportunity Fund. Want to join us? Visit http://www.techopportunityfund.org/. &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Point: $100 million fund launched for code school diversity scholarships</title><link href="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/04/code-school-diversity-scholarships.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Point: $100 million fund launched for code school diversity scholarships" /><published>2016-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/04/code-school-diversity-scholarships</id><content type="html" xml:base="/press/diversity/scholarship/2016/09/04/code-school-diversity-scholarships.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techpoint.org/2016/09/code-school-diversity-scholarships/&quot;&gt;TechPoint: $100 million fund launched for code school diversity scholarships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TechPoint: $100 million fund launched for code school diversity scholarships</summary></entry></feed>